SAFRIN PATIL Featured

Senior Associate seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Technical Analysis, Software Testing, Agile Methodology, Client Management, Service Management, Entity Framework, SQL Server, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, mvc core, Kendo UI, JQuery, GIT



Current Designation: Senior Associate - IT Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Opus Consulting Solutions Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Highest Degree: PG Diploma [Computers]

Current Location: Pune
Pref. Location: Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Associate, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Technical Analysis, Software Testing, Agile Methodology, Client Management, Service Management, Entity Framework, SQL

Server, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, ASP. Net MVC, Kendo Ui

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

Serving Notice-Period, I have experience of 7+ years as a Software Developer. To contribute my knowledge and skills for the betterment of an organization that provides an opportunity to explore my capacity. I believe in good teamwork, but I am also capable of working alone.

Work Experience

Opus Consulting Solutions as Senior Associate - IT Oct 2018 to Till Date

Victus?- It uses MVC Core 3, C#, Telerik UI, SQL Server, JSON, TFS, Web API Victus? is a payment solution that streamlines the way businesses buy & sell large ticket items. This is the first payment processing service designed around the purchase of equipment, machinery and parts and makes the entire experience simple

Bank Branding - It uses Asp.net MVC 5, C#, Angular JS, Azure SQL Server, XML, JSON, TFS, Entity Framework, Web API. This project is based on a pure payment domain where its task is to do the branding of different Banks to be get branded to a common framework. The several bank have ATMs vendor uses this application to manage the contracts of the ATMs, payment calculation, fetching of global rates using API.

Capgemini as Associate Consultant Jan 2016 to Sep 2018

ER Transformation - It uses Asp.net MVC 4, JQuery, Web API, WCF, C#, Git, SSIS. This application accepts consolidated input files from the user and generates different CSV files that are input to the TR tool. Flow is managed by SSIS packages. Input files are validated as per FATCA/CRS standards and then processed in the TR tool format

HASCue Technologies as Software Engineer

Apr 2015 to Dec 2016

CRM Redesign - It uses Asp.net MVC 4, JQuery, Web API, WCF, C#, SQL Server. CRM (Customer Relation Management system) application is mainly designed for Morgan Stanley Financial Advisor (FA) and Call Center Users, to maintain an interaction they have done with Morgan Stanley Client(s). This application is capable enough to generate a client

interactions report with various dimensions like Account, Interaction type, Communication time frame. This Product is very helpful to Morgan Stanley to maintain its customer as it reduces the change of Customer (swing) in case of if any Financial Advisor (FA) leaves the organization.

Ellai Information Systems Pvt. Ltd. as Software Engineer May 2014 to Mar 2015

Queue Management System - It uses Asp.net MVC4, C#, JQuery, LINQ, CSS SQL SERVER 2012, WCF, SSRS, TFS, Visual Studio 2013.

Queue Management system helps to organize the queues by providing visitors with virtual and linear queuing solutions, booked appointments. Appointment can be booked by KIOSK and also the queue ticket is getting printed or scanned from KIOSK system. The system allows for faster organization of queuing and customer service with its non-linear system. The system not only allows for a more effective customer service, but it analyses daily customer service transactions for an improved company performance.

Sahyadri Technologies as Software Developer

Apr 2013 to Apr 2014

Understanding the application and business, Coding, Testing, Implementation of the developed business solutions, Unit testing, system testing

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Hon Shri Annasaheb Dange College of Engineering and Technology in 2012

PG: PG Diploma (Computers) from Sunbeam Institute Of Technology in 2013

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Microsoft MVC Certified (70-486): Developing MVC Applications

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience		
MVC Core	3	2020	0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)		
Microsoft SQL Server	2018	2020	7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)		
.NET	3/4/4.5	2019	6 Year(s) 3 Month(s)		
C#	5/6	2020	7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)		
MVC	3/4/5	2020	7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)		
JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, LINQ		2019	6 Year(s) 3 Month(s)		
VISUAL STUDIO	2012, 2019	2020	7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)		
TFS		2019	6 Year(s) 3 Month(s)		
AJAX		2019	6 Year(s) 3 Month(s)		
Web API	2/3	2019	6 Year(s) 3 Month(s)		
WCF		2019	6 Year(s) 3 Month(s)		
ASP.Net MVC					
Web Service, XML, AJAX					
JavaScript, jQuery, Angular					
Bootstrap, Telerik UI Kendo			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)		
C#, LINQ, Entity Framework, Unit testing					

SQL Server 2018	2018	2020	7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
GIT, SVN, TFS			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Marathi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Victus Client: Product

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2020 - Till Date

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: It uses MVC Core 3, C#, Telerik UI, SQL Server, JSON, TFS, Web API Victus is a payment solution that streamlines the way businesses buy & sell large ticket items. This is the first payment processing service designed around the purchase of equipment, machinery and parts and makes the entire experience simple

Project Title: Bank Branding

Client: Cardtronics

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Oct 2018 - Till Date
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: This project is based on pure payment domain where its task is to do branding of different Banks to be get branded to a common framework. Several different types of bank have ATMs which are operated by a vendor, this vendor uses this application to manage all the contracts of the ATMs, payment calculation, fetching of global rates from different APIs. It also includes background level Windows services which do all the scheduled jobs for fetching data from APIs.

Project Title: ER Transformation

Client: Barclays Capital

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jun 2017 - Till Date
Project Location: Pune Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 6

Skill Used: ASP.NET MVC 4, JQuery, Web API, WCF, C#.NET, CSS, Git, Unit Testing Framework, DI Unity Container and

Mocking Framework, SSIS, DB2

Role Description: Requirement Gathering, Analysis, Development, Maintenance, Testing

Project Details: This application accepts consolidated input file from user and generates different csv files which are input to TR tool.

Flow is managed by SSIS packages.

Input files are validated as per FATCA/CRS standards and then processed in TR tool format.

Project Title: CRM Redesign Client: Morgan Stanley

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jun 2016 - May 2017
Project Location: Pune Duration: Jun 2016 - May 2017
Onsite / Offsite

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 15

Skill Used: ASP.NET MVC 4, JQuery, Web API, WCF, C#.NET, CSS, Teamcity, Stash, Git, Windeploy, Unit Testing Framework, DI Unity Container and Mocking Framework, DB2

Role Description: Designing, Coding and Maintenance.

Project Details: CRM (Customer Relation Management system) application is mainly designed for Morgan Stanley Financial Advisor (FA) and Call Center Users, to maintain an interaction they have done with Morgan Stanley Client(s). This application is capable enough to generate a client interactions report with various dimensions like Account, Interaction type,

Communication time frame. This Product is very helpful to Morgan Stanley to maintain their customer as It reduces change of Customer (swing) in case of if any Financial Advisor (FA) leaves the organization.

Modules:

Calendar: Calendar module allows Financial Advisor (FA) to schedule appointment and meeting for their client and team member related to their account FA can also create shared calendar. Calendar provides monthly, daily, week days and week view

Log2CRM: Log2CRM module is outlook plug-in, this plug-in allow Financial Advisor (FA) to tag their mail communication with client account so later on FA can see that email conversion from GWM C

Project Title: Human Resource Management System (HRMS) Client: Human Resource Management System (HRMS)

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2015 - Feb 2015 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Pune

Role: Programmer Team Size: 6 Skill Used: MVC4, Visual Studio 2012, SQL Server 2008, Entity framework, TFS

Role Description: Requirement Gathering, Designing, Coding

Project Details: The most important feature of the project is ONLINE ATTENDANCE SYSTEM with the help of ONLINE

ATTENDANCE an employee can put his attendance online.

Leave System (HRMS) maintains the leave details of employees. Employees record their attendance in the system. The system calculates the number of working days and the number of absent days and provides inputs to the payroll department. Leave applications are reconciled with the attendance records and the exceptions are highlighted. System caters to multiple types of leave (casual, privilege, sick etc.) and provides workflow for approval of leave applications. Employees can check their own leave and attendance records online.

Project Title: Immigration and Checkpoints Authority (ICA) Client: Immigration and Checkpoints Authority (ICA)

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Oct 2014 - Dec 2014 Project Location: Pune Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 6

Skill Used: ASP.NET MVC, C#.Net 4.5, SQL SERVER 2012, WCF, SSRS, TFS, Visual Studio 2013

Role Description: Understanding the application and business, Coding, Testing, Implementation of the developed business

solutions, Unit testing, system testing

Project Details: The Immigration & Checkpoints Authority (ICA) is responsible for the Singapore's borders against the entry of undesirable persons and cargo through our land, air and sea checkpoints. Aside from border security, ICA also performs immigration and registration functions such as the issuing of travel documents and identity cards to Singapore citizens. ICA also issues various immigration passes and permits to foreigners. As a security agency, ICA also conducts operations against immigration offenders.

Project Title: NHG POPULATION REGISTRY (NHG) Client: NHG POPULATION REGISTRY (NHG)

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2014 - Sep 2014

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Pune

Role: Programmer Team Size: 6

Skill Used: ASP.NET MVC4, C#.Net 4.5, SQL SERVER 2010, SVN, Visual Studio 2012

Role Description: Requirement Gathering, Designing, development

Project Details: NHG Population Registry is the system to capture and track Residents information in order to provide timely care:

To support coordinated management of health promotion and disease management intervention activities, and follow up with residents in the Central Region.

To support information sharing amongst units within NHG engaged in population health management.

Project Title: GodJodi.Com Client: Matrimonial Website Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Jan 2014 - Feb 2014 Project Location: satara Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 8

Skill Used: Visual Studio 2010, SQL Server 2008 R2, MVC3, Entity framework.

Role Description: Designing, Coding and Maintenance.

Project Details: This application is Matrimonial Website. Mainly three parts of this application which are Membership, Match point And Franchisee. The application has the capability to join the members and create their memberships, create different plans of Membership .Show the good matches for members as per their demand, Keep all the information of all franchisees and their joining and there earnings. I involved in Coding, Designing and Reporting.

Project Title: Inventory Management System Client: BrahmaChaitanya Traders Pvt Ltd.

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Oct 2013 - Dec 2013 Project Location: satara Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 8 Skill Used: Visual Studio 2010, SQL Server 2008 R2, MVC3, Entity framework.

Role Description: Designing, Coding and Maintenance.

Project Details: This is web application for supplying all facility of Inventory System. This application can be used for create billing / invoices; keeping product information, keeping stock information, reports also they can keep record s of their products and stock. This application provides a facility to keep records of their customer, supplier and also their transactions. I have involved in Coding & writing stored procedure

Project Title: MLM Website

Client: All Win InfoTech Pvt. Ltd, India. Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2013 - Nov 2013 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: satara

Role: Programmer Team Size: 6 Skill Used: Visual Studio 2010, SQL Server 2008 R2, MVC3, Entity framework.

Role Description: Designing, Coding and Maintenance.

Project Details: This System handles all the functionality of Multi Level Marketing from member joining to account Section, from Administration section to management section, payouts and invoices creation to members creation and mange all the activities of members. I have worked on Project management, Member Plans And Downline, Payouts Module.

Project Title: STPL Management Client: Clocking IT Software Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: satara Role: Programmer

Duration: Mar 2013 - Jul 2013 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 8

Skill Used: Studio 2010, SQL Server 2008 R2, MVC3, Entity framework.

Role Description: Designing, Coding and Maintenance.

Project Details: The project is STPL Management System which is a Web application which is build in MVC3 pattern and has wide scope. This project helps to create project and keep track of each project and number of employees working on it along with their number of hours spent on each project by each employee. We can calculate salary of each employee on the basis of their total work time. With the help of this software we can create task for employees.

Project Title: Clinic Management

Client: Doctor's

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Feb 2013 - Apr 2013 Project Location: satara Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 8

Skill Used: Visual Studio 2010, SQL Server 2008, Entity framework. Role Description: Designing, Coding and Maintenance.

Project Details: The project is Clinic Management System which is a desktop application which helps for doctors to manage their patients. This software allows to make entry of patient, add staff and doctors, add medicine stock, take reports on various regions like Gynaec prescription, general prescription, ANC prescriptions sonography reports and finally calculating sonography bill and patient bill. Thus helpful for small doctors who have their own OPD as well as doctors with their own large hospitals.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Countries: India

Employment Status: Full time